<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Martin Frigaard dot io</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Martin Frigaard dot io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Breadth of training -&gt; breadth of transfer (Range book review)</title>
      <link>/2019/09/27/breadth-of-training-breadth-of-transfer-range-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/27/breadth-of-training-breadth-of-transfer-range-book-review/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: this post is a short detour from the WW2 flying aces project. I took a small break from data projects to prepare for my tidyverse train the trainer certification from RStudio (read more about that here).
I was recently re-reading How to Teach Programming and Other Things, and in the section titled, “Repetition vs. Deliberate practice”, a quote stood out,
 A meta-study conducted in 2014 [Macnamara 2014] found that “.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Martin Frigaard, Data Scientist and Co-Founder of Paradigm Datagroup. I provide workshops, write tutorials, and build applications for anyone who works with data. I grew up in Sandy, Oregon, but I currently live in Oakland, California.
Projects and experience  I started as an analyst at the Center for Nutrition and Activity Promotion (now the Center for Healthy Communities) in 2010.
 After graduating with my MA in Kinesiology from California State University, Chico, I worked with a research and evaluation team on projects that investigated associations between blood pressure, obesity, and various medical conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrity in publishing (Ty Cobb: A Terrible Beauty book review)</title>
      <link>/2018/01/18/integrity-in-publishing-ty-cobb-a-terrible-beauty-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/18/integrity-in-publishing-ty-cobb-a-terrible-beauty-book-review/</guid>
      <description>I recently purchased and read Ty Cobb: A Terrible Beauty by Charles Leerhsen after watching his lecture at Hillsdale College. I’d always thought of Ty Cobb as the character portrayed by Tommy Lee Jones in the 1994 film Cobb. Even before seeing this film, Ty Cobb’s reputation for being rotten was pervasive–when referring to him in Field of Dreams, Shoeless Joe Jackson states, “No one liked that son of a bitch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>